Pedro Vieira

UX Designer / Graphic Designer

linkedin.com/in/pedro-vieira-design (+351) 964 399 343 www.pedrovieira.design hey@pedrovieira.design

About

UX designer, passionate about creativity and sustainability, with a background in graphic design.

Resourceful and creative problem solver, experienced in design thinking processes. Helped teams run through design cycles to explore, create and deliver user-focused, value-driven concepts for brands and products.

Skills

User-Centered Design

Design Thinking

Competitive Analysis

User Research

User Personas

Information Architecture

User Flows

Iterative Wireframing and Prototyping Usability and Preference Testing Language Systems and Styleguides HTML and CSS Fundamentals

Tools

Figma Miro
Illustrator Figjam
Photoshop After effects

Education

CareerFoundry

User Experience Design, UX Certification Intensive project-based mentored training program Mar 2022

IADE - Creative University

Postgraduate, Design Thinking & Prototyping Jul 2017

Polytechnic Institute of Castelo Branco

Bachelor's Degree, Visual Communication Design

Languages

Portuguese (Native)
English (Professional proficiency)

UX Projects

Viv - Health & Wellbeing app

UX/UI Designer - CareerFoundry Project

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

- Created an inclusive, responsive health web portal designed to help people manage daily health issues.
- Conducted user research, crafted wireframes and prototypes, analyzed usability tests results and implemented users' feedback.
- Refined designs according to accessibility principles and prepared them for dev handoff.

> View project < (link)

Speakin' - Language Learning app

UX Designer - CareerFoundry Project

Sep 2020 - Nov 2021

 Conceptualised a language learning mobile app by taking the project through design thinking stages, including competitive analysis, user research, information architecture, ideation, prototyping and user testing.

> View project < (link)

Professional Experience

Freelance Graphic Designer

Freelancer, Portugal

Since Sep 2009

 Worked for a diverse range of self-sourced clients, translating briefings into meaningful concepts and unique brand assets, resulting in strong visual identities in line with clients' culture and business objectives.

At Mendes Gonçalves S.A. / Santarém, Portugal

Creative Designer - Innovation Lab.

2017 - 2021

- Co-led a qualitative data-gathering project by designing an online store with food-product co-creation features, allowing for a direct connection with the target audience and a better understanding of consumers' needs.
- Re-designed the product innovation process, introducing user centered methods, ideation workshops and product prototyping, resulting in a fluid, iterative process and enabeling market-relevant outputs.

Graphic Designer - Brand Keeper

2012 - 2017

- Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team to revitalize the company's main brand, generating disruptive concepts that lead to a multi-awarded brand and increased top-of-mind awareness.
- Coordinated the brand application to online and offline assets, including website, online store and 200+ packaging items, ensuring visual guidelines adherence and delivering a consistent brand experience.

Graphic Designer - Junior

2009 - 2012

 Implemented visual identities across all print and digital marketing materials by continually collaborating with partners, suppliers, and departments, guaranteeing visual communication cohesion and boosting brand visibility.